Welcome to our lesson today.
I want to set the scene by starting off
by drawing a diagram to help you understand what the lesson plan is for today.
Drawing just helps me slow down my thoughts
and help us understand the context easier.
In our case,
overview is we're going to move the data
from a spreadsheet.
Or really a data table in Waikato
and get that over to a manager's cell phone.
To make a business decision.
So a very common one is
we have a new hire.
And these new hires have to have their laptop approved.
Uh,
by the hiring manager.
Oftentimes,
it's an email that gets sent,
but it often gets buried in their
mailbox and then there's a delay.
So,
what we're gonna do to make that function easier is we're going to build an iOS app
to make the approval function easier for the manager.
The data
and that data in this case is going to be who made the request,
what equipment,
uh,
what manager they are.
It'll be stored in a table,
which we see here.
We see here this table here,
and that will be stored in Ricardo.
In a future video,
I will review how we can fetch data from other recruitment systems.
So the overall goal here
in our system is two parts.
One,
Showing how to use Worcado to to build this API function,
and 2,
to use cloud code to build a user interface
for an iPhone that interacts with the Workado API.
So let me
begin by drawing the diagrams out.
So,
the first thing here we're gonna draw
is the data center for our,
uh,
to represent Rorcado.
So,
I'm just gonna draw a box here.
And then I'm just going to use the tool here to come up
with a suggestion.
So,
we're gonna type in data center.
And we're gonna make that request
and it's gonna start thinking about.
What image represents what I need,
and you'll notice that it's continuing to give these little circles at the
bottom means it's thinking about other options that I might be interested in.
And then also there's different styles,
so
I like the illustration style.
And I think this one is pretty good.
Well,
let's see what else,
yeah.
So I'm going to go with this one here and I'll click on the checkbox.
And this is going to represent our work auto system.
And then what I'm going to do here is just remove
uh the background.
And what are we going to store in there?
As I mentioned earlier,
we're going to store.
A
Data table
in Waikato,
which will represent the approval data,
the requests,
and then the response to that request.
So we'll just draw this box here.
Now it is thinking.
And I'll go with,
uh,
I'll go with this one here.
And
I'll go with illustration.
And I like that.
So,
click on there.
And I'm going to remove the background.
OK.
So this spreadsheet will represent the data
from Wakado.
And we will make,
uh,
request in between here.
Right?
That's going to be stored
in Mercado
with the information about the request users made
and the information whether that request was approved
or denied.
Now,
the next thing I want to represent that we're going to be looking to build is
the user interface.
Kind of a person.
And they're going to have a phone.
We'll go with that
and we'll check that.
And then I will remove the background.
Now that we have the user interface,
we're going to create an
app for iPhone
that will need to communicate with Workado,
and we will build 2 APIs in Workado.
The first one
Is
The phone will make a request on.
What are the pending requests?
And after it makes the request,
Ricardo will
return the data.
To the
app.
And then we'll display that.
There'll be two APIs I'll be demonstrating that we will build
to just demonstrate this behavior.